<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[AKHansen]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[AKHansen]]></description>
        <link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 04:28:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="undefinedrss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why We Must Exercise Care In Communicating Honor]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Why We Must Exercise Care In Communicating Honor</h1><p>I recently sat in a leadership meeting where we watched Jim Collins’ 2010 Global Leadership Summit talk (which on a side note – if you’re not planning on attending this year, change your plans and go!!!).

Mr. Collins spoke about the five stages of decline for organizations, the warning signs, and opportunities to change direction. The concepts were brilliant, and I’d definitely recommend setting aside some time to visit his website and read more on the subject.

The first stage is hubris born of success.


The best leaders we’ve studied never presume they’ve reached ultimate understanding of all the factors that brought them success.

– Jim Collins, A Primer on the Warning Signs
Mr. Collins continued to describe the leaders affected by hubris, stating that Level 5 Leaders don’t talk about themselves, they put the organization and its people first.

This got me thinking about church culture and the misuse of honor that has the potential to distract us from clearly communicating the Gospel message.

Church leadership coach Tony Morgan writes:

When an unhealthy “culture of honor” is promoted, God’s people wait for “God’s man” to do the work of God. That may work for someone who only intends to be a preacher, but it doesn’t work if you are trying to be a pastor.

Tony Morgan, The “Culture of Honor” is Hurting Churches
The Bible clearly values honor:

Be devoted to one another in love. Honor one another above yourselves.

– Romans 12:10 (NIV)
Our challenge is striking a balance between honor and hype.

Now before I go any further, I don’t want to give the impression that this is an easy topic to navigate. A culture of honor is NOT a bad thing to cultivate in your church. It’s important to lift each other up, demonstrate gratitude, and exercise humility. But as a leader in your church, it’s also important to communicate that honor goes up and down the chain of command.

So how do we as church communicators promote Biblical honor while keeping the Gospel as our central focus?

Celebrate people in your congregation first.
As communicators, we’re trying to inspire people to act in some way. As church communicators, we want to inspire people to choose Christ and engage in community.

By celebrating the people in your congregation first – their commitment to serving, life change, next steps taken – you communicate that you’re about people over projects and connection over numbers.

A great way to do this is by highlighting your volunteers on social media.

I’m fortunate to have many fanastic mentors in my life, but one of the longest standing and most influential has been Van Metschke.

Van taught me about honor by demonstrating it constantly. If you follow his Instagram or Twitter posts, he regularly highlights the volunteers serving under him, celebrating their milestones, hard work, and commitments to Christ. Van is a very accomplished leader, but he is always first to talk about the amazing work done by those around him.

When highlighting staff, make them relatable and avoid celebrity.
I’m fortunate to serve alongside amazing leaders at Willamette who seek their identities from Christ and exercise humility on a daily basis. When we communicate anything about or by a member of our team, we make every effort to focus on the work Christ is doing in and through the individual.

The easiest example to begin with is Sunday sermon quotes.

We will often create shareable graphics with message quotes from Sunday and attribute them to the author, but the post itself will focus on the point being made. Typically it will include some sort of prompt to encourage our congregation to respond by thinking about how the point can be applied to their everyday lives.

Now, this doesn’t mean highlighting your staff is a bad thing. In fact, one of the first pages a prospective visitor usually visits is your staff directory. Why? Because they want to see if they fit in!

A church staff is usually pretty reflective of the types of people you’ll find in the congregation. A visitor will find it comforting to see someone similar in age, race, gender, or even style.

Finding ways to showcase the unique people on your staff is helpful for those trying to figure out if your church is for them. One of the best ways to do this is by integrating your staff into regular communication. Use them in your videos (if they’re good on camera), have them write articles for your church blog, and make sure they post regularly on their personal social media accounts that are available to the public.

We can build a culture of honor in our churches that goes both ways. As one of the primary voices of our communities, we must focus on leading by example through humility in our communication.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>undefinedwhy-we-must-exercise-care-in-communicating-honor/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4f7c7465-8d1a-4686-8aca-529f6c1af1b1</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 04:27:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>